

ADEEL SARWAR

SQA Engineer

Contacts

E: adeelsarwar43@gmail.com

M: 0343-8484821

R: Lahore

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rana-adeel-6576bb89/

Professional Skills

- Black Box Testing
- Web App Testing
- Mobile App Testing
- Automation Testing
- Load Testing
- Stress Testing
- DB Testing
- MySQL

Tools

- ♦ Jira
- Cypress
- ♦ Imeter
- Postman & Swagger

Languages

- ♦ HTML
- ♦ CSS
- ♦ Bootstrap
- JavaScript

References

Name: Dr. Shujaat Hussain Mobile: 0333-5219820 Name: Dr. Subhan Ullah Mobile: 0343-9733083 Organi: NU-FAST Islamabad

Objective

Currently working as SQA Engineer at Conovo Technologies Lahore with more than 3 years of experience of quality assurance in different organizations including test planning, designing and execution. Talented in black-box testing, automation and web application testing; competent in multiple scripting languages. Excellent at quickly identifying high-level test strategies and problems. Collaborative but decisive personal style; effective communicator and problem solver. I also have experienced in teaching as I worked as Teaching Assistant in NU-FAST Islamabad.

Education

- Master's Degree in Software Engineering NU-FAST lsb 2021
- Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering UAF Fsd
 2017

Experience

| Position | SQA Engineer | Organization | Conovo Technologies |
|----------|------------------|--------------|------------------------|
| Location | Lahore, Pakistan | | _ |
| Current | Jul 2021 | | |

Duties:

- Lead the USA based Projects as QA named ABC Parking, Osce Al.
- Understand the medical terminologies for Osce AI medical based project.
- Writing TestCases of the product for documenation.
- > Perform UI testing and suggest the changes in the design.
- Perform Manual testing to check the product functionalities manually.
- Compare all the expected inputs with actual outputs.
- > Perform Automation testing using Cypress tool in JS language.
- Writing scripts to automate the flow for Smoke Testing.
- Using Imeter tool for load and stress testing.
- Using Jira for management process to report bugs and generate tickets.
- > Follow the scrum ceremonies in agile environment.
- Daily Standup meeting with the Team leads and members.

| Position | SQA Engineer | Organization | MTBC CareCloud |
|----------|--------------|--------------|-------------------|
| _ | | | |

Location Islamabad, Pakistan

Duration Feb 2021 – Jul 2021

Duties:

- Testing a medical product named CareCloud.
- Understand the medical terminologies and analyze product modules, flow, and design etc.
- Writing TestCases of different scenarios.
- UI testing comparing the actual module with moaks.
- Manual testing by doing the product functionalities manually.
- Compare all the expected inputs with actual outputs.
- Automation testing using Cypress JavaScript.
- Writing scripts to automate the flow for Smoke testing.
- Making a framework by integrating with Cocumber using Gherkin Language.
- > Checking the performance of the product by load and stress testing.
- > Checking the APIs by using Postman and Swagger tool.
- Performance testing by using Imeter tool.
- Writing the SQL queries for DB testing.
- Using Jira for the management process.
- > Follow the scrum ceremonies in agile environment.
- Daily Standup meeting with the USA Team leads and members.
- > Meetings with the Product owner, Product Manager/ Scrum Master and the Stackholders.

| Position | SQA (Project Based) | Organization | InfinityBits |
|----------|---------------------|--------------|--------------|
| Location | Islamabad, Pakistan | | |
| Duration | Feb 2020 – Feb 2021 | | |

Duties:

- Testing the developed projects.
- Perform testing on a mobile-based app Dobi Uncle.
- Testing the flow of the rider and the user for order and delivery.
- > Testing the admin pannel for app management.
- Perform testing on a mobile-based app Centrefy FRD which is a medical app.
- Testing the patient's medical record.
- Writing the TestCases for documentation.
- Making the bug report.

| Position | Teaching Assistant | Organization | NU-FAST |
|----------|--------------------|--------------|----------------|
| Location | Islamahad Pakistan | | |

Location Islamabad, Pakistan

Duration Sept 2019 – Feb 2020

Duties:

Teach the Software Engineering students, manage their activities.

- > Taking quizzes, assignments.
- > Solve the student's queries.
- Make their results.

| Position | SQA Research & Projects | Organization | NU-FAST Research Lab |
|----------|-------------------------|--------------|-------------------------|
| Location | Islamabad, Pakistan | | |
| Duration | Feb 2018 – Feb 2020 | | |

Duties:

- > Research the different testing techniques.
- Research paper on quality requirements.
- Term paper A survey on Unit Testing in Software Engineering
- > Term paper A survey on cost reduction techniques in Mutation Testing
- Term paper Non-Functional Testing
- Use tools to evaluate the work.
- Automation testing project-based by using Selenium tool
- Mutation testing by using MUJava as an assignment
- Write TestCases for testing

| Position | FYP | Organization | UAF |
|----------|----------------------|--------------|-----|
| Location | Faisalabad, Pakistan | | |
| Duration | Sept 2016 – Jun 2017 | | |

Duties:

- > Testing a zombie game.
- Perform all the UI testing.
- > Perform all the positive and negative functionality TestCases.
- Develop front end of a Clinical website using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Testing all the functionality of the website including UI, Positive and Negative scenarios.

Position Internship Organization Pasban IT

Location Faisalabad, Pakistan

Duration 3 Months

Duties:

> Learn Web development.

- Learn HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- > Try to make the front-end layout of the website.